http://www.opencms.org/en/privacy.html

Page content
Privacy Policy (Datenschutzerklärung)
We are very delighted that you have shown interest in our enterprise. Data protection is of a
particularly high priority for the management of the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG. The use of
the Internet pages of the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG is possible without any indication of
personal data; however, if a data subject wants to use special enterprise services via our website,
processing of personal data could become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary
and there is no statutory basis for such processing, we generally obtain consent from the data
subject.
The processing of personal data, such as the name, address, e-mail address, or telephone number
of a data subject shall always be in line with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and
in accordance with the country-specific data protection regulations applicable to the Alkacon
Software GmbH & Co. KG. By means of this data protection declaration, our enterprise would like
to inform the general public of the nature, scope, and purpose of the personal data we collect, use
and process. Furthermore, data subjects are informed, by means of this data protection declaration,
of the rights to which they are entitled.
As the controller, the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG has implemented numerous technical and
organizational measures to ensure the most complete protection of personal data processed through
this website. However, Internet-based data transmissions may in principle have security gaps, so
absolute protection may not be guaranteed. For this reason, every data subject is free to transfer
personal data to us via alternative means, e.g. by telephone.
1. Definitions
The data protection declaration of the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG is based on the terms
used by the European legislator for the adoption of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
Our data protection declaration should be legible and understandable for the general public, as
well as our customers and business partners. To ensure this, we would like to first explain the
terminology used.
In this data protection declaration, we use, inter alia, the following terms:
a)    Personal data
Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (“
data subject”). An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or
indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number,
location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical,
physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.
b) Data subject
Data subject is any identified or identifiable natural person, whose personal data is processed
by the controller responsible for the processing.
c)    Processing
Processing is any operation or set of operations which is performed on personal data or on sets
of personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organisation,
structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by
transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction,
erasure or destruction.
d)    Restriction of processing
Restriction of processing is the marking of stored personal data with the aim of limiting their
processing in the future.
e)    Profiling
Profiling means any form of automated processing of personal data consisting of the use of
personal data to evaluate certain personal aspects relating to a natural person, in particular to
analyse or predict aspects concerning that natural person's performance at work, economic
situation, health, personal preferences, interests, reliability, behaviour, location or
movements.
f)     Pseudonymisation
Pseudonymisation is the processing of personal data in such a manner that the personal data can
no longer be attributed to a specific data subject without the use of additional information,
provided that such additional information is kept separately and is subject to technical and
organisational measures to ensure that the personal data are not attributed to an identified or
identifiable natural person.
g)    Controller or controller responsible for the processing
Controller or controller responsible for the processing is the natural or legal person, public
authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and
means of the processing of personal data; where the purposes and means of such processing are
determined by Union or Member State law, the controller or the specific criteria for its nomination
may be provided for by Union or Member State law.
h)    Processor
Processor is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes
personal data on behalf of the controller.
i)      Recipient
Recipient is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or another body, to which the
personal data are disclosed, whether a third party or not. However, public authorities which may
receive personal data in the framework of a particular inquiry in accordance with Union or Member
State law shall not be regarded as recipients; the processing of those data by those public
authorities shall be in compliance with the applicable data protection rules according to the
purposes of the processing.
j)      Third party
Third party is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or body other than the data
subject, controller, processor and persons who, under the direct authority of the controller or
processor, are authorised to process personal data.
k)    Consent
Consent of the data subject is any freely given, specific, informed and unambiguous indication
of the data subject's wishes by which he or she, by a statement or by a clear affirmative action,
signifies agreement to the processing of personal data relating to him or her.
Name and Address of the controller
Controller for the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), other data
protection laws applicable in Member states of the European Union and other provisions related to
data protection is:
USt-IdNr.: DE259882372
Vertreten durch:
Cookies
The Internet pages of the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG use cookies. Cookies are text files
that are stored in a computer system via an Internet browser.
Many Internet sites and servers use cookies. Many cookies contain a so-called cookie ID. A
cookie ID is a unique identifier of the cookie. It consists of a character string through which
Internet pages and servers can be assigned to the specific Internet browser in which the cookie was
stored. This allows visited Internet sites and servers to differentiate the individual browser of
the dats subject from other Internet browsers that contain other cookies. A specific Internet
browser can be recognized and identified using the unique cookie ID.
Through the use of cookies, Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG can provide the users of this
website with more user-friendly services that would not be possible without the cookie setting.
By means of a cookie, the information and offers on our website can be optimized with the user
in mind. Cookies allow us, as previously mentioned, to recognize our website users. The purpose of
this recognition is to make it easier for users to utilize our website. The website user that uses
cookies, e.g. does not have to enter access data each time the website is accessed, because this is
taken over by the website, and the cookie is thus stored on the user's computer system.
The data subject may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies through our website by means
of a corresponding setting of the Internet browser used, and may thus permanently deny the setting
of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or
other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. If the data subject
deactivates the setting of cookies in the Internet browser used, not all functions of our website
may be entirely usable.Collection of general data and information
The website of the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG collects a series of general data and
information when a data subject or automated system calls up the website. This general data and
information are stored in the server log files. Collected may be (1) the browser types and versions
used, (2) the operating system used by the accessing system, (3) the website from which an
accessing system reaches our website (so-called referrers), (4) the sub-websites, (5) the date and
time of access to the Internet site, (6) an Internet protocol address (IP address), (7) the
Internet service provider of the accessing system, and (8) any other similar data and information
that may be used in the event of attacks on our information technology systems.
When using these general data and information, the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG does not
draw any conclusions about the data subject. Rather, this information is needed to (1) deliver the
content of our website correctly, (2) optimize the content of our website as well as its
advertisement, (3) ensure the long-term viability of our information technology systems and website
technology, and (4) provide law enforcement authorities with the information necessary for criminal
prosecution in case of a cyber-attack. Therefore, the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG analyzes
anonymously collected data and information statistically, with the aim of increasing the data
protection and data security of our enterprise, and to ensure an optimal level of protection for
the personal data we process. The anonymous data of the server log files are stored separately from
all personal data provided by a data subject.Subscription to our mailing list
On the website of the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG, users are given the opportunity to
subscribe to our enterprise's mailing list. The input mask used for this purpose determines what
personal data are transmitted, as well as when the newsletter is ordered from the controller.
The Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG offers the mailing list as a tool for communication. The
enterprise's mailing list may only be received by the data subject if (1) the data subject has a
valid e-mail address and (2) the data subject registers for the mailing list shipping. A
confirmation e-mail will be sent to the e-mail address registered by a data subject for the first
time for mailing list shipping. This confirmation e-mail is used to prove whether the owner of the
e-mail address as the data subject is authorized to receive the mailing list.
During the registration for the mailing list, we also store the IP address of the computer
system assigned by the Internet service provider (ISP) and used by the data subject at the time of
the registration, as well as the date and time of the registration. The collection of this data is
necessary in order to understand the (possible) misuse of the e-mail address of a data subject at a
later date, and it therefore serves the aim of the legal protection of the controller.
The personal data collected as part of a registration for the mailing list will only be used to
send our mailing list. In addition, subscribers to the mailing list may be informed by e-mail, as
long as this is necessary for the operation of the mailing list service or a registration in
question, as this could be the case in the event of modifications to the mailing list offer, or in
the event of a change in technical circumstances. There will be no transfer of personal data
collected by the mailing list service to third parties. The subscription to our mailing list may be
terminated by the data subject at any time. For the purpose of revocation of consent, a
corresponding link is found in each e-mail of the mailing list.Contact possibility via the website
The website of the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG contains information that enables a quick
electronic contact to our enterprise, as well as direct communication with us, which also includes
a general address of the so-called electronic mail (e-mail address). If a data subject contacts the
controller by e-mail or via a contact form, the personal data transmitted by the data subject are
automatically stored. Such personal data transmitted on a voluntary basis by a data subject to the
data controller are stored for the purpose of processing or contacting the data subject. There is
no transfer of this personal data to third parties.Comments function for the pages of the website
The Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG offers users the possibility to leave individual comments
on certain pages of the website of the controller.
If a data subject leaves a comment on the pages of this website, the comments made by the data
subject are also stored and published, as well as information on the date of the commentary and on
the user's (pseudonym) chosen by the data subject. In addition, the IP address assigned by the
Internet service provider (ISP) to the data subject is also logged. This storage of the IP address
takes place for security reasons, and in case the data subject violates the rights of third
parties, or posts illegal content through a given comment. The storage of these personal data is,
therefore, in the own interest of the data controller, so that he can exculpate in the event of an
infringement. This collected personal data will not be passed to third parties, unless such a
transfer is required by law or serves the aim of the defense of the data controller.Routine erasure and blocking of personal data
The data controller shall process and store the personal data of the data subject only for the
period necessary to achieve the purpose of storage, or as far as this is granted by the European
legislator or other legislators in laws or regulations to which the controller is subject to.
If the storage purpose is not applicable, or if a storage period prescribed by the European
legislator or another competent legislator expires, the personal data are routinely blocked or
erased in accordance with legal requirements.Rights of the data subject
a) Right of confirmation
Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the
controller the confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning him or her are being
processed. If a data subject wishes to avail himself of this right of confirmation, he or she may,
at any time, contact any employee of the controller.
b) Right of access
Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the
controller free information about his or her personal data stored at any time and a copy of this
information. Furthermore, the European directives and regulations grant the data subject access to
the following information:
the purposes of the processing;
the categories of personal data concerned;
the recipients or categories of recipients to whom the personal data have been or will be
disclosed, in particular recipients in third countries or international organisations;
where possible, the envisaged period for which the personal data will be stored, or, if not
possible, the criteria used to determine that period;
the existence of the right to request from the controller rectification or erasure of personal
data, or restriction of processing of personal data concerning the data subject, or to object to
such processing;
the existence of the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority;
where the personal data are not collected from the data subject, any available information as
to their source;
the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling, referred to in Article 22(1)
and (4) of the GDPR and, at least in those cases, meaningful information about the logic involved,
as well as the significance and envisaged consequences of such processing for the data
subject.
Furthermore, the data subject shall have a right to obtain information as to whether personal
data are transferred to a third country or to an international organisation. Where this is the
case, the data subject shall have the right to be informed of the appropriate safeguards relating
to the transfer.
If a data subject wishes to avail himself of this right of access, he or she may, at any time,
contact any employee of the controller.
c) Right to rectification
Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the
controller without undue delay the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning him or her.
Taking into account the purposes of the processing, the data subject shall have the right to have
incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.
If a data subject wishes to exercise this right to rectification, he or she may, at any time,
contact any employee of the controller.
d) Right to erasure (Right to be forgotten)
Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the
controller the erasure of personal data concerning him or her without undue delay, and the
controller shall have the obligation to erase personal data without undue delay where one of the
following grounds applies, as long as the processing is not necessary:
The personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were
collected or otherwise processed.
The data subject withdraws consent to which the processing is based according to point (a) of
Article 6(1) of the GDPR, or point (a) of Article 9(2) of the GDPR, and where there is no other
legal ground for the processing.
The data subject objects to the processing pursuant to Article 21(1) of the GDPR and there are
no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing, or the data subject objects to the processing
pursuant to Article 21(2) of the GDPR.
The personal data have been unlawfully processed.
The personal data must be erased for compliance with a legal obligation in Union or Member
State law to which the controller is subject.
The personal data have been collected in relation to the offer of information society services
referred to in Article 8(1) of the GDPR.
If one of the aforementioned reasons applies, and a data subject wishes to request the erasure
of personal data stored by the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG, he or she may, at any time,
contact any employee of the controller. An employee of Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG shall
promptly ensure that the erasure request is complied with immediately.
Where the controller has made personal data public and is obliged pursuant to Article 17(1) to
erase the personal data, the controller, taking account of available technology and the cost of
implementation, shall take reasonable steps, including technical measures, to inform other
controllers processing the personal data that the data subject has requested erasure by such
controllers of any links to, or copy or replication of, those personal data, as far as processing
is not required. An employees of the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG will arrange the necessary
measures in individual cases.
e) Right of restriction of processing
Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the
controller restriction of processing where one of the following applies:
The accuracy of the personal data is contested by the data subject, for a period enabling the
controller to verify the accuracy of the personal data.
The processing is unlawful and the data subject opposes the erasure of the personal data and
requests instead the restriction of their use instead.
The controller no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but they
are required by the data subject for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
The data subject has objected to processing pursuant to Article 21(1) of the GDPR pending the
verification whether the legitimate grounds of the controller override those of the data
subject.
If one of the aforementioned conditions is met, and a data subject wishes to request the
restriction of the processing of personal data stored by the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG, he
or she may at any time contact any employee of the controller. The employee of the Alkacon Software
GmbH & Co. KG will arrange the restriction of the processing.
f) Right to data portability
Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator, to receive the
personal data concerning him or her, which was provided to a controller, in a structured, commonly
used and machine-readable format. He or she shall have the right to transmit those data to another
controller without hindrance from the controller to which the personal data have been provided, as
long as the processing is based on consent pursuant to point (a) of Article 6(1) of the GDPR or
point (a) of Article 9(2) of the GDPR, or on a contract pursuant to point (b) of Article 6(1) of
the GDPR, and the processing is carried out by automated means, as long as the processing is not
necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of
official authority vested in the controller.
Furthermore, in exercising his or her right to data portability pursuant to Article 20(1) of the
GDPR, the data subject shall have the right to have personal data transmitted directly from one
controller to another, where technically feasible and when doing so does not adversely affect the
rights and freedoms of others.
In order to assert the right to data portability, the data subject may at any time contact any
employee of the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG.
g) Right to object
Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to object, on grounds
relating to his or her particular situation, at any time, to processing of personal data concerning
him or her, which is based on point (e) or (f) of Article 6(1) of the GDPR. This also applies to
profiling based on these provisions.
The Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG shall no longer process the personal data in the event of
the objection, unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which
override the interests, rights and freedoms of the data subject, or for the establishment, exercise
or defence of legal claims.
If the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG processes personal data for direct marketing purposes,
the data subject shall have the right to object at any time to processing of personal data
concerning him or her for such marketing. This applies to profiling to the extent that it is
related to such direct marketing. If the data subject objects to the Alkacon Software GmbH &
Co. KG to the processing for direct marketing purposes, the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG will
no longer process the personal data for these purposes.
In addition, the data subject has the right, on grounds relating to his or her particular
situation, to object to processing of personal data concerning him or her by the Alkacon Software
GmbH & Co. KG for scientific or historical research purposes, or for statistical purposes
pursuant to Article 89(1) of the GDPR, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a
task carried out for reasons of public interest.
In order to exercise the right to object, the data subject may contact any employee of the
Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG. In addition, the data subject is free in the context of the use
of information society services, and notwithstanding Directive 2002/58/EC, to use his or her right
to object by automated means using technical specifications.
h) Automated individual decision-making, including profiling
Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator not to be subject to a
decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects
concerning him or her, or similarly significantly affects him or her, as long as the decision (1)
is not is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract between the data subject
and a data controller, or (2) is not authorised by Union or Member State law to which the
controller is subject and which also lays down suitable measures to safeguard the data subject's
rights and freedoms and legitimate interests, or (3) is not based on the data subject's explicit
consent.
If the decision (1) is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract between
the data subject and a data controller, or (2) it is based on the data subject's explicit consent,
the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG shall implement suitable measures to safeguard the data
subject's rights and freedoms and legitimate interests, at least the right to obtain human
intervention on the part of the controller, to express his or her point of view and contest the
decision.
If the data subject wishes to exercise the rights concerning automated individual
decision-making, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the Alkacon Software GmbH
& Co. KG.
i) Right to withdraw data protection consent
Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to withdraw his or her
consent to processing of his or her personal data at any time.
If the data subject wishes to exercise the right to withdraw the consent, he or she may, at any
time, contact any employee of the Alkacon Software GmbH & Co. KG.
Data protection for applications and the application procedures
The data controller shall collect and process the personal data of applicants for the purpose of
the processing of the application procedure. The processing may also be carried out electronically.
This is the case, in particular, if an applicant submits corresponding application documents by
e-mail or by means of a web form on the website to the controller. If the data controller concludes
an employment contract with an applicant, the submitted data will be stored for the purpose of
processing the employment relationship in compliance with legal requirements. If no employment
contract is concluded with the applicant by the controller, the application documents shall be
automatically erased four months after notification of the refusal decision, provided that no other
legitimate interests of the controller are opposed to the erasure. Other legitimate interest in
this relation is, e.g. a burden of proof in a procedure under the General Equal Treatment Act
(AGG).Data Protection provisions about the application and use of AddThis
On this website, the data controller has integrated components of the enterprise AddThis.
AddThis is a so-called bookmarking provider. The service allows for simplified bookmarking of
Internet pages via buttons. By clicking on the AddThis component with the mouse, or by clicking on
it, a list of bookmarking and sharing services is displayed. AddThis is used on over 15 million
websites, and the buttons are displayed, according to the information of the operating enterprise,
over 20 billion times a year.
The operating company of AddThis is AddThis, Inc. 1595 Spring Hill Road, Suite 300, Vienna, VA
22182, United States.
By calling up one of the individual pages of the website, which is operated by the controller,
and on which an AddThis component has been integrated, the Internet browser of the data subject is
automatically prompted by the respective AddThis component to download data from the website
www.addthis.com. Within the framework of this technical procedure, AddThis is informed of the visit
and the specific individual page of this website that was used by the data subject with the help of
information technology. In addition, AddThis is informed about the IP address of the computer
system assigned by the Internet service provider (ISP) and used by the data subject, the browser
type and language, the web page accessed before our website, the date and the time of the visit to
our website. AddThis uses this data to create anonymous user profiles. The data and information
transmitted to AddThis in this way will enable the enterprise AddThis, as well as affiliates or
their partner-enterprises, to contact visitors of the web pages of the controller with personalized
and interest-based advertising.
AddThis displays personalized and interest-based advertising on the basis of a cookie set by the
enterprise. This cookie analyzes the individual surfing behavior of the computer system used by the
data subject. The cookie saves the computer-based outgoing visits to Internet pages.
The data subject may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies through our website by means
of a corresponding setting of the Internet browser used, and thus permanently deny the setting of
cookies. Such a setting of the Internet browser used would also prevent AddThis from setting a
cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. Cookies may also be deleted by
AddThis at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs.
The data subject also has the possibility of objecting permanently to the processing of personal
data by AddThis. For this purpose, the data subject must click on the opt-out button under the link
http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out, which sets an opt-out cookie. The opt-out cookie used for
this purpose is placed on the information technology system used by the data subject. If the data
subject deletes the cookies from his system, then the data subject must call up the link again and
set a new opt-out cookie.
With the setting of the opt-out cookie, however, the possibility exists that the websites of the
controller are not fully usable anymore by the data subject.
The applicable data protection provisions of AddThis may be accessed under
http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy.Data protection provisions about the application and use of SlideShare
On this website, the controller has integrated SlideShare components. LinkedIn SlideShare as a
file hosting service allows you to exchange and archive presentations and other documents, such as
PDF files, videos, and webinars. The file hosting service allows users to upload media content in
all popular formats, with the documents either publicly-accessible or private-labeled.
The operating company of SlideShare is LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court Mountain View,
CA 94043, United States. For privacy matters outside of the United States the LinkedIn Ireland,
Privacy Policy Issues, Wilton Plaza, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland, is responsible.
LinkedIn SlideShare provides so-called embedded codes for the media content (e.g. presentations,
PDF files, videos, photos, etc.) stored there. Embedded codes are program codes that are embedded
in the Internet pages to display external content on their own website. Embedded codes allow
content to be reproduced on its own website without storing it on its own server, possibly
violating the right of reproduction of the respective author of the content. A further advantage of
the use of an embedded code is that the respective operator of a website does not use its own
storage space and the own server is thereby relieved. An embedded code may be integrated at any
point on another website so that an external content may also be inserted within the own text. The
purpose of using LinkedIn SlideShare is to relieve our server and to avoid copyright infringements,
while at the same time using third-party content.
With each call-up to our Internet site, which is equipped with a SlideShare component (embedded
code), this component prompts the browser that you are using to download the according embedded
data from SlideShare. During the course of this technical procedure, LinkedIn gains knowledge of
which specific sub-page of our website is visited by the data subject.
If the data subject is logged in on SlideShare at the same time, SlideShare recognizes with each
call-up to our website by the data subject and for the entire duration of their stay on our
Internet site which specific sub-page was visited by the data subject. This information is
collected by SlideShare and assigned to the respective SlideShare account of the data subject
through LinkedIn.
LinkedIn obtains information via the SlideShare component that the data subject has visited our
website, provided that the data subject is logged in at SlideShare at the time of the call-up to
our website. This occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on the embedded media data or not.
If such a transmission of information to SlideShare is not desirable for the data subject, then he
or she may prevent this by logging off from their SlideShare account before a call-up to our
website is made.
LinkedIn also uses affiliates such as Eire, Google Analytics, BlueKai, DoubleClick, Nielsen,
Comscore, Eloqua, and Lotame. The setting of such cookies may be denied under
https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy. The applicable data protection provisions for
LinkedIn is available under https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy.Data protection provisions about the application and use of YouTube
On this website, the controller has integrated components of YouTube. YouTube is an Internet
video portal that enables video publishers to set video clips and other users free of charge, which
also provides free viewing, review and commenting on them. YouTube allows you to publish all kinds
of videos, so you can access both full movies and TV broadcasts, as well as music videos, trailers,
and videos made by users via the Internet portal.
The operating company of YouTube is YouTube, LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, UNITED
STATES. The YouTube, LLC is a subsidiary of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA
94043-1351, UNITED STATES.
With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the
controller and on which a YouTube component (YouTube video) was integrated, the Internet browser on
the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download a
display of the corresponding YouTube component. Further information about YouTube may be obtained
under https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/en/. During the course of this technical procedure, YouTube
and Google gain knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data
subject.
If the data subject is logged in on YouTube, YouTube recognizes with each call-up to a sub-page
that contains a YouTube video, which specific sub-page of our Internet site was visited by the data
subject. This information is collected by YouTube and Google and assigned to the respective YouTube
account of the data subject.
YouTube and Google will receive information through the YouTube component that the data subject
has visited our website, if the data subject at the time of the call to our website is logged in on
YouTube; this occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on a YouTube video or not. If such a
transmission of this information to YouTube and Google is not desirable for the data subject, the
delivery may be prevented if the data subject logs off from their own YouTube account before a
call-up to our website is made.
YouTube's data protection provisions, available at
https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/, provide information about the collection,
processing and use of personal data by YouTube and Google.Data protection provisions about the use of PayPal as a payment processor
On this website, the controller has integrated components of PayPal. PayPal is an online payment
service provider. Payments are processed via so-called PayPal accounts, which represent virtual
private or business accounts. PayPal is also able to process virtual payments through credit cards
when a user does not have a PayPal account. A PayPal account is managed via an e-mail address,
which is why there are no classic account numbers. PayPal makes it possible to trigger online
payments to third parties or to receive payments. PayPal also accepts trustee functions and offers
buyer protection services.
The European operating company of PayPal is PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l. & Cie. S.C.A., 22-24
Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg, Luxembourg.
If the data subject chooses "PayPal" as the payment option in the online shop during the
ordering process, we automatically transmit the data of the data subject to PayPal. By selecting
this payment option, the data subject agrees to the transfer of personal data required for payment
processing.
The personal data transmitted to PayPal is usually first name, last name, address, email
address, IP address, telephone number, mobile phone number, or other data necessary for payment
processing. The processing of the purchase contract also requires such personal data, which are in
connection with the respective order.
The transmission of the data is aimed at payment processing and fraud prevention. The controller
will transfer personal data to PayPal, in particular, if a legitimate interest in the transmission
is given. The personal data exchanged between PayPal and the controller for the processing of the
data will be transmitted by PayPal to economic credit agencies. This transmission is intended for
identity and creditworthiness checks.
PayPal will, if necessary, pass on personal data to affiliates and service providers or
subcontractors to the extent that this is necessary to fulfill contractual obligations or for data
to be processed in the order.
The data subject has the possibility to revoke consent for the handling of personal data at any
time from PayPal. A revocation shall not have any effect on personal data which must be processed,
used or transmitted in accordance with (contractual) payment processing.
The applicable data protection provisions of PayPal may be retrieved under
https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full.Legal basis for the processing
Art. 6(1) lit. a GDPR serves as the legal basis for processing operations for which we obtain
consent for a specific processing purpose. If the processing of personal data is necessary for the
performance of a contract to which the data subject is party, as is the case, for example, when
processing operations are necessary for the supply of goods or to provide any other service, the
processing is based on Article 6(1) lit. b GDPR. The same applies to such processing operations
which are necessary for carrying out pre-contractual measures, for example in the case of inquiries
concerning our products or services. Is our company subject to a legal obligation by which
processing of personal data is required, such as for the fulfillment of tax obligations, the
processing is based on Art. 6(1) lit. c GDPR. In rare cases, the processing of personal data may be
necessary to protect the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person. This
would be the case, for example, if a visitor were injured in our company and his name, age, health
insurance data or other vital information would have to be passed on to a doctor, hospital or other
third party. Then the processing would be based on Art. 6(1) lit. d GDPR. Finally, processing
operations could be based on Article 6(1) lit. f GDPR. This legal basis is used for processing
operations which are not covered by any of the abovementioned legal grounds, if processing is
necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by our company or by a third party,
except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of
the data subject which require protection of personal data. Such processing operations are
particularly permissible because they have been specifically mentioned by the European legislator.
He considered that a legitimate interest could be assumed if the data subject is a client of the
controller (Recital 47 Sentence 2 GDPR).The legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party
Where the processing of personal data is based on Article 6(1) lit. f GDPR our legitimate
interest is to carry out our business in favor of the well-being of all our employees and the
shareholders.Period for which the personal data will be stored
The criteria used to determine the period of storage of personal data is the respective
statutory retention period. After expiration of that period, the corresponding data is routinely
deleted, as long as it is no longer necessary for the fulfillment of the contract or the initiation
of a contract.Provision of personal data as statutory or contractual requirement; Requirement necessary to enter into a contract; Obligation of the data subject to provide the personal data; possible consequences of failure to provide such data
We clarify that the provision of personal data is partly required by law (e.g. tax regulations)
or can also result from contractual provisions (e.g. information on the contractual partner).
Sometimes it may be necessary to conclude a contract that the data subject provides us with
personal data, which must subsequently be processed by us. The data subject is, for example,
obliged to provide us with personal data when our company signs a contract with him or her. The
non-provision of the personal data would have the consequence that the contract with the data
subject could not be concluded. Before personal data is provided by the data subject, the data
subject must contact any employee. The employee clarifies to the data subject whether the provision
of the personal data is required by law or contract or is necessary for the conclusion of the
contract, whether there is an obligation to provide the personal data and the consequences of
non-provision of the personal data.Existence of automated decision-making
As a responsible company, we do not use automatic decision-making or profiling.
This Privacy Policy has been generated using the Privacy Policy Generator of the
DGD - Your
External DPO that was developed in cooperation with
German Lawyers from WILDE BEUGER SOLMECKE, Cologne.
To the fast access
Right column
Latest News
OpenCms 11.0.2 available
Aug 18, 2020 - OpenCms 11.0.2 is a maintenance release for OpenCms 11. This version fixes a number of issues that have been detected in OpenCms 11.0.1. Also included are a number of security enhancements.
Release Notes for OpenCms 11.0.2
Aug 18, 2020 - The OpenCms 11.0.2 release notes contain detailed information about the new features and fixes in this version.
Alkacon OCEE 11.0.2 for OpenCms 11 available
Aug 14, 2020 - Alkacon OCEE 11.0.2 is an important update that fixes issues in the license validation. Alkacon OCEE 11 compared to previous versions brings an all new OCEE user interface as well as improved and more secure cluster configuration options. Moreover, OCEE from version 11 features a new license key mechanisam that allows to share the license key in a cloud installation.
OpenCms 11.0.1 available
Sep 4, 2019 - OpenCms 11.0.1 is a maintenance release for OpenCms 11. This version fixes a number of issues that have been detected in OpenCms 11. Also included are some new features and security enhancements.
To the fast access
Subnavigation
News
Guided tour introduction
Solution Providers
Reference sites
Downloads
To the fast access
